Victor Catamo Rojas <a href="https://catamo.github.io/">https://catamo.github.io/</a>

## Mobile: +420 725 913 045

Email: victor.catamo.rojas@gmail.com

## **Description**

Software Engineer with a Bachelor's degree in Informatics Engineering and more than 5 years of experience developing software. My area of expertise is Web Application Development, working as a Fullstack Developer. I am comfortable using C# along .NET Framework and Core and Node.js with Express. I also know my way around Frontend technologies like Vue.js and React.js, and use tools like Docker and Jenkins in my development workflow.

### Skillset

**Current Stack:** .NET Core, Node, Vue **Databases:** SQL Server, MongoDB

**Programming Languages:** C#, JavaScript, Python **Spoken Languages:** English, Spanish

## **Experience**

**Techona** *Software Engineer* 

Prague, Czech Republic *May 2019 - December 2019* 

- Casino games developer, using an internal JavaScript framework of the company. Which was a wrapper for Pixi JS, and used Google Closure Library to enable modularity.
- In my latest project I was part of a 5 persons team, with only 2 being developers. As the framework had little documentation most of my development process was seeing other projects and talking with developers more experienced in it.
- In a solo project, which took one month, I managed to reduce the time needed to create
  a new development project in Jira from days to just minutes by developing an Excel AddIn
  that integrated with the company's Jira REST API, which was coded using VSTO with C#.
  The company used a template of common tasks for each project, and the Project
  Managers had to manually create each and every one of the tasks in Jira. Now the tools
  even handles task hierarchy and deals with custom fields that are needed for reports.

# The App Master Software Developer

Buenos Aires, Argentina July 2018 - August 2019

- Senior developer for a reengineering project for one of the main online theater ticket sellers in argentina. The project took 1 year and fulfilled all the requirements asked by the client, with some others that arose during development.
- Worked as part of a 2 developers team, participating in all the stages of the project, including: Project planning, create Database scripts, project structure, infrastructure, and much more. The solution consisted on 3 projects, one of them was a Back Office application made using JQuery and ASP.NET MVC, with .NET Framework 4.7.2. Another was a REST API made using .NET Core, which shared .NET Standard libraries with the Back Office. And lastly, the Frontend was made using Vue.js.
- Implemented Continuous Integration using Jenkins as a Build Server, thus improving release times by 90%, compared to the old FTP release process. It took me a week to learn and implement the Jenkins builds successfully.

#### Hexacta

Software Developer

- Worked developing internal tools for an US company specialized in risk management solutions for the workers' compensation, auto, health and disability management industries.
- As part of team of 3 developers, I worked on a ASP.NET WebForms project that handled most of its logic in Stored Procedures. I improved Production Environments Performance by an average of 20%, replacing cross-applies and cursors with more efficient alternatives.
- Worked on the Frontend of a new project tasked with handling bulk data loading into SQL Server databases hosted in Azure to later on be replicated to physical databases in the client's offices. The solution was made with ASP.NET Core MVC, Entity Framework Core, Kendo UI and TypeScript, everything hosted on Azure as well.

**Freelancer** *Software Developer* 

Remote, Venezuela January 2017 - July 2017

- Created a proof of concept of Microsoft Bot Framework for SiderysBSN that integrated with Outlook and set up meetings for you from Skype.
- Implemented Twillio video calls between Mobile and Web for a startup named HLink iFarmacias. The solution was made using ASP.NET MVC and JQuery

**GIGA I.T.** *Software Developer* 

Remote, Venezuela June 2016 - May 2017

- Developed a new module to dynamically handle bulk loads to the database from spreadsheets with different layouts. Implemented it using ASP.NET MVC and OpenXML, using Hangfire handle the longer processes in the background.
- Worked in bug fixing and implementing new modules for multiple ASP.NET MVC projects.

**Norkut** *Entry-Level Software Developer* 

Nueva Esparta, Venezuela February 2015 - June 2016

**Norkut** *Software Development Intern* 

Nueva Esparta, Venezuela April 2014 - November 2014

### **Education**

### Universidad de Margarita

Ingeniero de Sistemas (Bachelor of Informatics Engineering)

Porlamar, Venezuela 2010 - 2015

Multidisciplinary degree that combines engineering with informatics. In one hand it has courses like Calculus, Physics and Operations Research. On the other hand, the students learn about Programming, Data Structures, Databases and Computer Architecture.